<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://www.spoilsofeternity.com/blog</id>
    <title>Spoils of Eternity Blog</title>
    <updated>2023-02-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.spoilsofeternity.com/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Spoils of Eternity Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://www.spoilsofeternity.com/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[February 2023]]></title>
        <id>February 2023</id>
        <link href="https://www.spoilsofeternity.com/blog/February 2023"/>
        <updated>2023-02-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Getting back into it after taking some time off over the winter. Happy to come back to this with fresh eyes and a renewed perspective, and see how much was done before taking a break for the winter.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Getting back into it after taking some time off over the winter. Happy to come back to this with fresh eyes and a renewed perspective, and see how much was done before taking a break for the winter. </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="todo-for-development-purposes">TODO For development purposes<a class="hash-link" href="#todo-for-development-purposes" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><ol><li>Create a new <code>Equipment Item Interface</code> script to replace the existing. Merge functionality from the new <code>Item Slot Interface Controller</code> which was created for the new interface and layout and likely contains the appropriate shader logic for highlighting the selected slot. Otherwise, can leverage the existing functionality that was built for the equipment item slot. </li><li>Will also probably want to rewrite the <code>Player Equipment Interface Controller</code>, but there's certainly some logic that I don't want to rewrite (calculating item stat deltas comes to mind).</li><li>Need to figure out what buttons will appear in the equipment interface. The wireframes have a button which would display other items of the selected slot, which hasnt been developed yet. </li><li>Increase current and next character level font size</li><li>Update loot filter interface<ol><li>background</li><li>text</li><li>checkboxes</li><li>close button</li></ol></li><li>Update the main menu to reflect the new approach<ol><li>Character creation doesn't make much sense as there is only one class currently</li><li>For the sake of keeping focus narrow, do not allow multiple characters?</li></ol></li><li>Make life as a developer a little easier. Add functionality to seed in a number of items to the inventory. </li><li>Display something in the main interface to inform the user they have <code>n New Items In Inventory</code> or something like that. Also indicate that they have skill points?</li></ol><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="questionsdecisions">Questions/Decisions<a class="hash-link" href="#questionsdecisions" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><ol><li></li></ol><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="bugsfixes">Bugs/Fixes<a class="hash-link" href="#bugsfixes" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><ol><li>Omnisharp was throwing an error which I resolved by setting <code>"omnisharp.useGlobalMono"</code> in <code>settings.json</code> to <code>1.39.2</code>. It was previously set to <code>latest</code>. I did this because of the instructions at <a href="https://github.com/microsoft/vscode/issues/170031" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://github.com/microsoft/vscode/issues/170031</a>. I probably want this to eventually be set back to latest</li></ol>]]></content>
        <category label="update" term="update"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Character Class and Skill Tree]]></title>
        <id>roadmap</id>
        <link href="https://www.spoilsofeternity.com/blog/roadmap"/>
        <updated>2022-11-20T22:38:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Since I had already attempted to create multiple character classes, there will be some effort to remove content in the name of progress.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started working on creating audio for the game and got sidetracked for a majority of October making an album of music to use as background focus music while programming. Time well spent? Not sure. But I need to pick back up on this, which will be a challenge, because I stopped in the middle of implementing skill functionality, genericizing some functionality and data structure into scriptable objects. Since that will be tough to jump back into, I need to create some low-hanging fruit items to get the momentum going. So, why not a roadmap?</p><p>Multi-character functionality isn't top priority for an MVP. Having a single class to get the core gameplay in place seems more achievable. So-</p><ol><li><p>One character class with a skill tree</p></li><li><p>Different acts</p><p>a. Different item types/progression</p><p>b. Improved odds of unique item drop for some bosses?
</p></li><li><p>Different mob types in the acts</p></li><li><p>A few different enemy types (melee, ranged, caster, tank) to create some variation. </p></li><li><p>Refine some of the art to get rid of the super serious aesthetic. The art doesn't match the game, and I think creates inaccurate assumptions that the game simply wont satisfy.</p></li><li><p>Create unique items that are actually unique, and provide somegame-changing functionality beyond just stat modifications</p></li><li><p>Leaderboards, or something that will incentivize playing the game</p></li><li><p>On the subject of playing the game, improve the interactability ofthe core gameplay loop, so that it's more than just a fire-and-forgetidle game.</p></li><li><p>Add audio to the game. And reduce how ridiculous it is with loudsound effects on every hit</p></li><li><p>Maybe some type of cloud-driven auction house? Probably not an MVP item. </p></li><li><p>Update the way acts and levels are managed. Create themes for the different acts, and update the waypoint screen with some art for each of the different acts.</p></li></ol>]]></content>
        <category label="roadmap" term="roadmap"/>
        <category label="skill tree" term="skill tree"/>
        <category label="class" term="class"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[November Update]]></title>
        <id>November Update</id>
        <link href="https://www.spoilsofeternity.com/blog/November Update"/>
        <updated>2022-11-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It seems that the direction of the game for v1 will be a single set of skills, one character class, and a number of passive skills that can modify how the game is played, which somewhat helps circumvent the need for multiple character classes. But, the skill tree needs to be usable, and not overly complicated, as the goal is primarily accessibility.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It seems that the direction of the game for v1 will be a single set of skills, one character class, and a number of passive skills that can modify how the game is played, which somewhat helps circumvent the need for multiple character classes. But, the skill tree needs to be usable, and not overly complicated, as the goal is primarily accessibility. </p><ol><li><p>Add passive skill tree</p></li><li><p>Capture and track unlocked passives</p></li><li><p>Add a few new movement skill mechanics</p><p>a. Add leap skill</p><p>b. Add lunge skill</p></li><li><p>Add enemy ability which applies DoT to area (which will force use of movement mechanic skill. Maybe this is undesirable if the player does not have control over movement)</p></li></ol><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="todo-for-development-purposes">TODO For development purposes<a class="hash-link" href="#todo-for-development-purposes" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><ol><li>DONE- Add combat arena scene to build and test </li><li>Most of the player components require the CharacterManager. Maybe create a single PlayerDataManager that exists on the player, and all the player components can then reference the PlayerDataManager, which would contain the single reference point to the CharacterManager. This would also make it possible to move dependency away from the CharacterManager?</li><li>Swap the PlayerSkills around so that that class references the PlayerController. Currently, PlayerController references PlayerSkills</li><li>Maybe create a generic post skill action cooldown that active skills can set, instead of having the attack cooldown check each of the skills independently. In PlayerSkills, create an ActionSkillCooldown, and then each of the action skill scan set the actionSkillCooldown when the skill is used. </li></ol><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="questionsdecisions">Questions/Decisions<a class="hash-link" href="#questionsdecisions" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><ol><li>Almost every ARPG on the app store is designed for landscape ratio. This is likely due to the movement/joystick layout. However, I don't want to force landscape layout. The more successful games seem to largely prioritize portrait controls, which I think encourages/appeals to a more casual audience. I suppose in typing this out/thinking through, I've convinced myself to stick with portrait format. Even if I do add movement mechanics, Ubisoft was able to pull it off with Mighty Quest (RIP)</li><li>Last Epoch provides a training dummy instead of raw DPS values/calculations. This does make it a bit more difficult to decide on upgrades, but encourages trial and error for builds vs. using whatever minmax strategy is the first result on youtube. Maybe the combat arena scene can act as a way to test a build. This would be a nice feature for users, but additional development. For now, will keep that possible use-case in mind while building out the arena (for design and debug purposes)</li></ol>]]></content>
        <category label="update" term="update"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2023 Roadmap]]></title>
        <id>roadmap</id>
        <link href="https://www.spoilsofeternity.com/blog/roadmap"/>
        <updated>2022-11-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I started working on creating audio for the game and got sidetracked for a majority of October making an album of music to use as background focus music while programming. Time well spent? Not sure. But I need to pick back up on this, which will be a challenge, because I stopped in the middle of implementing skill functionality, genericizing some functionality and data structure into scriptable objects. Since that will be tough to jump back into, I need to create some low-hanging fruit items to get the momentum going. So, why not a roadmap?]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started working on creating audio for the game and got sidetracked for a majority of October making an album of music to use as background focus music while programming. Time well spent? Not sure. But I need to pick back up on this, which will be a challenge, because I stopped in the middle of implementing skill functionality, genericizing some functionality and data structure into scriptable objects. Since that will be tough to jump back into, I need to create some low-hanging fruit items to get the momentum going. So, why not a roadmap?</p><p>Multi-character functionality isn't top priority for an MVP. Having a single class to get the core gameplay in place seems more achievable. So-</p><ol><li><p>One character class with a skill tree</p></li><li><p>Different acts</p><p>a. Different item types/progression</p><p>b. Improved odds of unique item drop for some bosses?
</p></li><li><p>Different mob types in the acts</p></li><li><p>A few different enemy types (melee, ranged, caster, tank) to create some variation. </p></li><li><p>Refine some of the art to get rid of the super serious aesthetic. The art doesn't match the game, and I think creates inaccurate assumptions that the game simply wont satisfy.</p></li><li><p>Create unique items that are actually unique, and provide somegame-changing functionality beyond just stat modifications</p></li><li><p>Leaderboards, or something that will incentivize playing the game</p></li><li><p>On the subject of playing the game, improve the interactability ofthe core gameplay loop, so that it's more than just a fire-and-forgetidle game.</p></li><li><p>Add audio to the game. And reduce how ridiculous it is with loudsound effects on every hit</p></li><li><p>Maybe some type of cloud-driven auction house? Probably not an MVP item. </p></li><li><p>Update the way acts and levels are managed. Create themes for the different acts, and update the waypoint screen with some art for each of the different acts.</p></li></ol>]]></content>
        <category label="roadmap" term="roadmap"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[About Spoils of Eternity]]></title>
        <id>about</id>
        <link href="https://www.spoilsofeternity.com/blog/about"/>
        <updated>2022-09-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Development of Spoils of Eternity began in August 2022]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Development of Spoils of Eternity began in August 2022</p>]]></content>
        <category label="About" term="About"/>
    </entry>
</feed>